snapvine.com 2017-06-30

# Privacy Policy | Whitepages

**Last updated on April 6, 2017.**

This privacy policy is designed to provide you with information regarding data collection and use in connection with our products and services. This policy explains how Whitepages uses the data collected by its Web sites, products, and services, but does not apply to databases or third parties that we do not control. 

## A. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

### 1\. Why do we collect data?

We collect data in order to effectively provide useful products and services to you and others. We also use this data to improve the quality of those products and services. 

### 2\. What kind of data do you collect?

We collect information such as: 

(a) Contact and demographic data. We may collect your first and last name, email address, postal address, phone number, and other similar contact data. We also may collect data about you such as your age, country, and preferred language. 

(b) Account credentials. We collect passwords and similar security information used for authentication and account access. 

(c) Usage data. We collect data about how you use our products and services. This includes, but is not limited to, data such as the search terms you enter, the pages you visit, and the items you purchase. We may also collect data about your device such as IP address, device identifiers, and data about the network, operating system, or software you use to connect to our products and services. 

(d) Location data. When you enable location-based features of our products, we may collect location data, such as GPS coordinates. We may also collect location data derived from your IP address. 

(e) Payment data. If you make a purchase, we collect data necessary to process your payment, such as your name, credit card number, and security code. 

When you are asked to provide personal data, you may decline. But if you choose not to provide data that is necessary to provide a service, you may not be able to use some features or services. 

### 3\. How do you collect data?

The data we collect depends on the services and features of our products that you use. You provide some data directly, such as when you create an account, submit a search query, or contact us for support. Our servers collect information known as “log data” that includes your IP address, when your computer or device visited the site, the URL of the Web site you arrived from, and the type of device or browser you used to access the site. We also get information by recording how you use our services and whether you navigate between our services. For example, we use cookies (small text files placed on your device) and may receive usage data from software running on your device. 

### 4\. Do you get data anywhere else?

We obtain information about users (and non-users) from third party sources, including surveys or questionnaires, data licensors, public records, affiliated entities, marketing companies, and other consumers who use our products. We use this information to validate and enrich information in our databases so that we can provide and improve services to users of our products. The terms of this privacy policy do not apply to data used in our databases that we have obtained from third party sources. 

### 5\. How do you use the information you collect?

We use data to provide useful products and services, and customer support, to our users. We also use data to verify information we have received from public and third-party sources, to help us analyze the usage and effectiveness of our products and services, and to improve our products and services. We may use data to resolve disputes and enforce our agreements, and to protect our users against fraud and abuse. We may also use data to send you communications, including promotional communications, or to serve advertising to you. 

### 6\. Do you share the data you collect? Why?

We share your data as necessary to complete any transaction or provide any service you have requested or authorized. For example, when you provide payment data to make a purchase, we will share payment data with entities that process payment transactions, and for fraud prevention and credit risk reduction. Besides the consumer users of Whitepages’s products and services, we may also provide data to our business users (e.g., corporate fraud departments) so that they may identify and verify their customers or potential customers, or conduct other legitimate business interests. 

We may share data with companies working on our behalf, such as vendors we may have hired to provide customer service. We may disclose and sell data as part of a corporate transaction such as a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, or sale of assets. We also share data when we have a good faith belief that doing so is necessary to comply with applicable law, to respond to a legal process, such as a subpoena, or to help prevent the loss of life or serious injury of anyone. Finally, we may provide access to non-personally-identifiable information to our third party advertisers so that they can deliver relevant online and mobile advertising to you. 

### 7\. How do you protect my information?

We have implemented commercially reasonable precautions to protect the information we collect from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Please be aware that despite our best efforts, no data security measures can guarantee 100% security. 

You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer/phone, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, and keeping your log-in and password private. We are not responsible for any lost, stolen, or compromised passwords or for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity. 

### How do I access and control my personal information?

You may use your account to access, correct, or change any personal information that you have provided to us or that is otherwise associated with your account. You may also email our customer support team support@whitepages.com. We will respond to your request within 30 days. Please note that your ability to correct or change your personal information does not extend to information that we have received from third parties. 

If you would like to stop receiving marketing materials messages from Whitepages, please provide us with the email address you would like to unsubscribe by mailing support@whitepages.com. Please note that you may still receive account and billing notices from us, if applicable. 

## B. INFORMATION COLLECTED BY THIRD PARTIES

### 1\. What information is collected by third parties when I use your products?

Third parties may collect information during your visits to our Web sites and use of our mobile products and services. Such information includes searches you perform (e.g., category of business, location) and general information about you (e.g., browser type, mobile device type, unique user ID, mobile carrier, IP address, date and time of your visits, locality, pages viewed). Certain products and services may collect specific information such as your name, phone number, IP address, etc., but unless you provide specific details about yourself, information collected by such third parties will generally be limited to non-personally-identifiable information. 

### 2\. How is information collected by third parties?

Third parties may collect information by using cookies, web beacons, or GPS information. A cookie is a small file that contains a unique ID tag and stores information (e.g., pages visited, information voluntarily provided). A web beacon is a small graphic file used to identify if a page has been viewed. GPS information may include city, state and other information when you use our products or services on a GPS-enabled mobile device. 

### 3\. Why do these third parties collect information?

Third parties may collect information in order to (i) deliver relevant online and mobile advertising to you both on and off our sites; (ii) help us provide or analyze usage and effectiveness of our products and services; and (iii) for their own business purposes (e.g., such as to report aggregate, non-personally identifiable information about the use of their services and technologies). 

### 4\. How will they use the information they collect? Will they share it?

Collection and use of data is subject to the privacy policies of the third party companies with whom we work, such as the privacy policy of [AdMarvel](http://operamediaworks.com/site-privacy-policy) or [Google](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/). Accordingly, please review those policies for specific information. If you prefer not to have your data collected and analyzed by Google, you may install the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

### 5\. How do I stop the collection and use of my information by third parties?

To stop collection of information in connection with the use of our products and services, you will need to stop using them. To opt-out of Whitepages mobile app marketing program tracking, [click here](https://www.optoutmobile.com/). To stop collection of browsing information via supporting web browsers, [click here](http://donottrack.us/). To stop information collection for purposes of relevant online advertising, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). At this time, there is no industry solution to opt-out of receiving relevant mobile advertising, but to opt-out of tracking from Whitepages’s own mobile app marketing programs, go to our third party provider’s Web site by [clicking here](https://www.optoutmobile.com/). 

### 6\. What about interest-based advertising?

We follow the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising (about the collection and use of data for interest-based advertising) and expect third parties to comply with the disclosure and notification program specified by principles. This means that third parties collecting and using this data are asked to provide a standard icon/link in or near their advertisements that will provide you with additional data about their privacy and advertising practices, as well as with the opportunity to directly opt-out of having your information collected. To stop receiving interest-based advertising, [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). 

## C. MISCELLANEOUS

### 1\. Children's privacy

Our services are not intended for children under the age of 18. We do not knowingly publish information for anyone under the age of 18. If you know of anyone under the age of 18 whose information is published through our services, or have other concerns about children's privacy, please write to Whitepages Privacy Manager, 1301 Fifth Ave, Suite 1600, Seattle, WA 98101 or contact Customer Service at [support@whitepages.com](mailto:support@whitepages.com)

### 2\. Changes to the Privacy Policy

Please see the date at the top of this page for information about when it was last updated. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. 

### 3\. How do I contact you?

If you have any questions about this policy, please write to Whitepages Privacy Manager, 1301 Fifth Ave, Suite 1600, Seattle, WA 98101 or contact Customer Service at [support@Whitepages.com](mailto:support@whitepages.com).
